MOHD FAISAL

Associate Software Engineer

- **** 7839309007
- www.linkedin.com/in/mohd-faisal-1993aa246
- @ mohdfaisal7839@gmail.com
- Lucknow , Uttar Pradesh, India



SUMMARY

Passionate Associate Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience in developing web applications and mobile applications. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environments as needed by the company.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Graduate Trainee

HCLTech

苗 09/2023 - Present 👂 Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh , India

- · Expertise customer handling experience.
- Expertise in delivery and program management, requirement and business analysis, planning and execution of projects.
- Extensive experience in various phases of SDLC such as requirement analysis, planning, execution and operations management.

Associate Software Engineer

Elint Minds

- · Developed, implemented userfriendly mobile applications using the Flutter
- Assisted with senior developers and designers to create and integrate UI/UX designs into the applications.
- Integrated thirdparty libraries, APIs, state Management Tools, Mail integration and services to enhance app capabilities and identified and fixed bugs to ensure app stability and performance.
- Develop Web applications using React js, HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT and maintain a responsive website, user friendly.

Software Developer Intern

Analyze Infotech

苗 07/2022 - 09/2022 👂 Lucknow , Uttar Pradesh, India

Develop Desktop Application using Java/J2SE as a frontend and MySQL as a backend

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Application

University of Lucknow

High School and Intermediate

Ram Prasad Bismil School

SKILLS

TOOLS

Android Studio

Visual Studio Code

Git

Github

MongoDB

MySQL

LANGUAGES

Java HTML

CSS

JavaScript

FRAMEWORKS

React is

Flutter

Firebase

Redux

Bootstrap

CS FUNDAMENTALS

Object-Oriented Programming (OOPs)

Database Management System

PROJECTS

Cozii Proptech

=== 11/2022 - 02/2022

Location

An app for taking homes on rent and also for providing Homes on rent it contain three modules Landlord, Handyman, Tenant develop using Flutter for UI development. Firebase for authentication and authorization of users identity.

E-commerce

An app for buying and selling products develop using Flutter.

Firebase, RESTAPI, Mail Integration.

Seed Inc

A App for posting images, videos and share with your friends. This app developed using Flutter, Firebase, Mail Integration, RESTAPI, State Management tool.

YouTube Clone

YouTube Clone website for watching daily uploaded videos.